Al Jawhara Abdulrahman Al Ruzaihy

0557727295/ aljawaharaalruzaihy@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

A Saudi national, extraordinary activist with an accumulated 8 years of hands- on expertise in Human Resources services, succeeded in growing and developing businesses through the application of best practices along with local success stories in HR supervision of a wide range of sectors and with well-known organizations, aiming to reach at the highest ranks that please my ambitions and fit our country and community.

Eager to continue and develop HR services to meet the objectives of providing quality value added services.

EDUCATION AND ACADEMIA

Al Imam Mohammed Bin Saud University

Bachelor in Business Administration

2015

PERSONALITY AND PROFESSIONAL TRAITS

- · Team building and Leadership
- Quality oriented
- Strategic planning
- Free thinker and change management
- Crisis management
- Department's supervision
- Building and developing organizations communication

CAREER HISTORY

Current: Miahona Company since May 2020 till date Talent Acquisition Senior Officer

- Develop and update job descriptions and job specifications
- Source and attracting candidates using a variety of search methods and database.
- Screen candidates by reviewing resumes and job applications and performing phone screenings.
- Conducting interviews and filtering candidates for open positions
- Manage onboarding and new hire process
- Manage the overall interview, selection, and closing process
- Ensure all screening, hiring, and selection is done in accordance with employment laws and regulations
- Designing and implementing the overall recruiting strategy
- Promoting and enabling necessary changes to align operations with strategic plans.
- Resolving understaffing issues, disputes, employee terminations and disciplinary procedures.
- Collaborating with leadership to assess and improve policies across board.
- Managed full cycle of recruiting, hiring and onboarding new employees.
- Reviewing job descriptions & occupational classifications.
- Provide full support to the Business Development Department in all projects

MetLife AIG ANB Cooperative insurance company since May 2015 till May 2019 HR Senior Supervisor

Main responsibilities:

- Assist in the administration of all personnel policies and procedures.
- Provide advice to line managers on best practice in all aspects of employment, including company policies and legislation.
- Provide an advisory service to all employees and employee representatives on company employment policies and procedures.
- Maintain regular contact with managers to establish their recruitment needs and carry out all necessary procedures to meet those needs.
- Monitor and record absence levels in each department and provide statistical data to managers in relation to these.
- Monitor and apply personnel policies and procedures as directed by the personnel manager.
- Annalise job requirements and prepare job descriptions and person specifications for recruitment, job evaluation and other purposes and coordinate all stages of the hiring process
- Assess employee engagement and retention, and actively work to identify, analyze, and improve any problematic areas.

King Saud University (Nov 2011 - Apr 2015)

Project Manager Secretary – Maintenance Supervisor

- Handle administrative requests and queries from senior managers
- Organizing and scheduling appointments with admin software
- Planning meetings and taking detailed minutes

Princess Nora University (Feb 2009 – Jan 2011)

HR Officer

- Assist in the administration of all HR policies and procedures.
- Maintain regular contact with managers to establish their recruitment needs and carry out all necessary procedures to meet those needs.
- Monitor and record absence levels in each department and provide statistical data to managers in relation to these.
- Monitor and apply personnel policies and procedures as directed by the HR manager.
- Analyse job requirements and prepare job descriptions and person specifications for recruitment, job evaluation and other purposes.

Specialist Medical Centre (Aug 2008 - Dec 2008)

HR secretary

- Perform general secretarial duties for the Human Resources Office
- Answer questions from and act as liaison between the Human Resources Manager and employees, should the Human Resources Manager be unavailable

Al Jazirah Bank (Jan 2008 - July 2008)

Sales Assistant

- Ensuring high levels of customer satisfaction through excellent sales service
- Assist with the sales process

OTHER TRAINING CERTIFICATIONS

- PMP
- ICDL
- IFCE
- English Language British Council Intermediate level
- Diploma in Electrical, mechanical engineering
- Culture of telework administratively
- Labor Education according to Saudi Labor Law
- Managing Project Risks
- The Fundamentals of Event Management
- Assistant Underwriting 1
- Assistant Underwriting 2
- Cyber Security (stc)
- Fundamentals and Principles of Financial Accounting Part 1 & 2